UMAIR ARSHAD

493 H2 Johar Town, Lahore

umair6622@gmail.com

+923006622188

www.linkedin.com/in/umair-arshad-butt

CAREER PROFILE

Experienced Software Engineer with over one year of experience. Excellent reputation for building websites and web applications. Experienced in front end development. I also have experience of working in various Programming languages as mentioned in my skills. And seeking for more opportunities in other fields to work.

EDUCATION

FAST NUCES, BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (2019)

SKILLS & ABILITIES

LANGUAGES AND FRAMWORKS

JavaScript – Excellent	Typescript - Excellent	Java – Excellent
Markdown – Good	Angular JS – Excellent	Angular7 – Good
JQuery – Excellent	HTML – Excellent	CSS – Excellent
Grails – Good	PSD to HTML- Good	JBake- Good
Groovy – Good		

DATABASE

MySQL / SQL- Good

TECHNOLOGIES

RESTFul API – Excellent	GIT – Excellent	AJAX – Excellent
JSON – Excellent		

TOOLS

Web Storm – Excellent	VS Code – Excellent	Intellij – Excellent	
Xampp – Excellent	Jira – Good	Slack – Excellent	

OPERATING SYSTEMS

Windows – Excellent Linux – Excellent

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer-Frontend Engineer Shahi Sawar PVT- (Sep 2019 - Present)

- Delivering a complete front end application.
- Ensuring high performance on mobile and desktop.
- Coordinating the workflow between the graphic designer, the HTML coder, and yourself.
- Cooperating with the back-end developer in the process of building the RESTful API.
- Communicating with external web services.
- Ensure high quality graphic standards and brand consistency.
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies.
- Write functional requirement documents and guides.

Software Engineer Jfreaks – (Feb 2019 – Sep 2019)

- Familiarity with JAVA.
- Work on JBake Ensuring high performance on mobile and desktop.
- Communicating with external web services.
- Ensure high quality graphic standards and brand consistency.
- Stay up-to-date on emerging technologies.

Teacher Assistant FAST NUCES – (Jun 2018 – Aug 2018)

- Distributed learning materials such as worksheets, textbooks and supplemental activities.
- Supported instructor with test administration, curriculum development and assignment grading.

Developed following Websites:

- IP Geolocation
 - https://ipgeolocation.io/
- FloKids
 - https://flokids.com/
- FLO
 - https://rideflo.com/

INTERESTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Secured First position in Computer Logic Design Project system.
- Global Peace Ambassador.
- Learning new technologies.
- Books Reading.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST